<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xsl-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../transforms/xsl/module/module2html.xsl"?>

<?xml-model href="../transforms/schemas/CCModule.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>



<Module boilerplate="yes" target-product="Session Border Controller" 
  name="Session Border Controller"
  xmlns="https://niap-ccevs.org/cc/v1"
  xmlns:sec="https://niap-ccevs.org/cc/v1/section"
  xmlns:h="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
 
  <PPReference>
    <ReferenceTable>
      <PPVersion>1.0</PPVersion>
      <PPAuthor>National Information Assurance Partnership</PPAuthor>
      <PPPubDate>2022-09-09</PPPubDate>
      <Keywords>Session Border Controller</Keywords>
    </ReferenceTable>
  </PPReference>
  <RevisionHistory>
    <entry>
      <version>1.0</version>
      <date>2022-08-12</date>
      <subject>Initial Release</subject>
    </entry>
  </RevisionHistory>
  
  
  <!-- TODO: see Issues for open items -->
  
  <sec:Introduction>
    <sec:Overview>
      The scope of this Protection Profile Module (PP-Module) is to describe the security functionality of a Session Border Controller (SBC) in terms of [CC] and to define functional and assurance requirements for such products. 
      This PP-Module is intended for use with the following Base-PPs:
      <h:ul>
        <h:li>collaborative Protection Profile for
          Network Devices, Version 2.2e (NDcPP)</h:li>
      </h:ul>
      This Base-PP is valid because a device that implements an SBC is a specific type of network device, 
      and there is nothing about the implementation of an SBC that would prevent any of the security capabilities defined by the Base-PP from being satisfied.
      <h:p/>
      Note that the NDcPP defines an optional architecture for a “distributed TOE” that allows for security functionality to be spread across multiple distinct components. 
      This PP-Module does not require or prohibit the TOE from being a distributed system when the TOE conforms to the NDcPP; the TOE may be standalone or distributed in this case.
      
    </sec:Overview>
    <tech-terms>
      <suppress>Functional Package,Extended Package</suppress>
      <term abbr="ACL"  full="Access Control List"/>
      <term abbr="B2BUA"  full="Back-To-Back User Agent"/>
      <term abbr="CDR"  full="Call Detail Record"/>
      <term abbr="DPI"  full="Deep Packet Inspection"/>
      <term abbr="ESC" full="Enterprise Session Controller">
        A voice/video over IP (VVoIP) infrastructure device that is used to set up and tear down calls between VVoIP endpoints.
      </term>
      <term full="H.323">
        A communications protocol defined by ITU-T that is used for creating, modifying, and terminating multimedia sessions with multiple participants.
      </term>
      <term abbr="IETF"  full="Internet Engineering Task Force"/>
      <term abbr="IP-PBX"  full="Internet Protocol Public Branch Exchange"/>
      <term abbr="ITU-T"  full="ITU Telecommunication Standardization Sector"/>
      <term abbr="MGCP" full="Media Gateway Control Protocol">
        A means of communication between a media gateway and a media gateway controller.
      </term>
      <term abbr="NAT"  full="Network Address Translation"/>
      <term abbr="RTCP"  full="RTP Control Protocol"/>
      <term abbr="RTP"  full="Real-Time Transport Protocol"/>
      <term abbr="PSTN"  full="Public Switched Telephone Network"/>
      <term abbr="SDES"  full="Security Descriptions for Media Streams"/>
      <term abbr="SDP"  full="Session Description Protocol"/>
      <term abbr="SIP" full="Session Initiation Protocol">
        A communications protocol defined by IETF that is used for creating, modifying, and terminating multimedia sessions with multiple participants.
      </term>
      <term abbr="SRTP" full="Secure Real-Time Transport Protocol">
        A protocol that is used to provide multimedia (voice/video) streaming services with added security of encryption, message authentication and integrity, and replay protection.
      </term>
      <term abbr="VVoIP"  full="Voice/Video Over IP"/>
      
      

    </tech-terms>
    <sec:Compliant_Targets_of_Evaluation>
      This PP-Module specifically addresses SBCs that provide firewalling, interoperability, and security functions for VVoIP networks. 
      The SBC also provides protected communication between trusted components of the network infrastructure.
      <h:p/>
      The physical boundary of the SBC is defined by the operating system components storing or providing security functions and 
      all software supplied by the vendor, including vendor modified components to the operating system. 
      All of the security functionality is contained and executed within the physical boundary of the device.
      <h:p/>
      While the functionality that the TOE is obligated to implement in response to the described threat environment is detailed in later sections, 
      a brief description is provided here. A compliant TOE will provide security functionality that addresses threats to itself. 
      It must also protect communications between itself and an Internet Protocol Public Branch Exchange (IP-PBX) 
      or another SBC by using a trusted channel. Some protocols required by this PP-Module make use of certificates; therefore, the SBC must securely store certificates and private keys. 
      <h:p/>
      Since this PP-Module builds on the NDcPP, conformant TOEs must implement the functionality required in the NDcPP along 
      with the additional functionality defined in this PP-Module in response to the threat environment discussed later in this document.
      
    </sec:Compliant_Targets_of_Evaluation>
      <sec:TOE_Boundary>
        An SBC is a security device composed of hardware and software connected to two or more distinct voice networks that provides security and interoperability functions. 
        SBCs are deployed between peering service provider networks, service provider networks and enterprise networks, 
        service provider networks and residential customers, or in some cases as a back-to-back user agent (B2BUA) that allows mobile users the ability to connect to their internal VVoIP network.
        <h:p/>
        The following diagram represents a typical deployment of the TOE and its operational environment (OE). 
        Note that the TOE boundary is limited to the physical boundary of the SBC device itself and the trusted channels/paths that are established by the SBC.
        <h:p/> <comment>[JF] Note figure has known issues (blurry, figure title in actual image, duplicate trusted channel entry in key). Will need to re-make if editable version doesn't exist</comment>
	     <h:p/>
        <figure entity="images/figure1.png" title="SBC Deployment Model" id="OperEnv"/>
        <h:p/>
      </sec:TOE_Boundary>
    
    
    <sec:Use_Cases>
      This PP-Module defines a single potential use case for the SBC TOE:
      <usecases>
        <usecase id="usecase-dedicated" title="Border Protection">
          <description>The TOE is a specialized network device that provides firewall services for VVoIP networks. 
            The TOE is intended to provide protection against well-known threats that target these networks. 
            The SBC examines headers and data values of packets and compares them to an Access Control List (ACL) to either permit or deny them to the SBC or through the SBC. 
            The SBC is typically deployed between service providers for security, interoperability, translation, and transcoding purposes; 
            between service providers and residential customers for security and interoperability purposes; or between service providers and enterprise networks for translation, transcoding, and security purposes. 
            The SBC, as a border element, should also be able to establish a secure communication channel with external devices it communicates with. .</description>
        </usecase>

      </usecases> 
    </sec:Use_Cases> 
  </sec:Introduction>
  <sec:Conformance_Claims boilerplate="no">
    <cclaims>
      <cclaim name="Conformance Statement">
        <description>
	  <h:p>
	    This PP-Module inherits exact conformance as required from the specified
            Base-PP and as defined in the CC and CEM addenda for Exact Conformance, Selection-Based
          SFRs, and Optional SFRs (dated May 2017).</h:p>
	  <h:p>
            No PPs or PP-Modules may be specified in a PP-Configuration with this PP-Module other than the Base-PP specified
	    in <xref to="Overview"/>.
	  </h:p>
        </description>
      </cclaim>
      <cclaim name="CC Conformance Claims">
        <description>This PP-Module is conformant to Parts 2 (extended) and 3 (conformant) of Common
          Criteria Version 3.1, Release 5 [CC]. </description>
      </cclaim>
      <cclaim name="Package Claims">
        <description>This PP-Module does not
          claim conformance to any packages.</description>
      </cclaim>
    </cclaims>
  </sec:Conformance_Claims>
  <sec:Security_Problem_Description>
    The security problem is described in terms of the threats that the TOE is expected to address, assumptions about its Operational Environment, and any organizational security policies that the TOE is expected to enforce.
    <sec:Threats>
      The following threats that are defined in this PP-Module extend the threats that are defined by the Base-PP.
      <threats>
        <threat name="T.MALICIOUS_TRAFFIC">
          <description>An attacker may attempt to send malformed packets to the SBC in order to cause the network stack or services listening on TCP/UDP ports on the SBC or protected network to crash.</description>
          <consistency-rationale>
            The Base-PP does not define a threat for malicious traffic because all of its security-relevant external interfaces define the network device as the endpoint. 
            This PP-Module defines interfaces where the TOE is facilitating a connection between two external entities, 
            such that traffic between them will flow through the TOE as opposed to to/from the TOE. 
            This threat is consistent with the Base-PP because it is only applied to the interfaces defined in this PP-Module where it is relevant; it does not apply to the interfaces defined in the Base-PP.
          </consistency-rationale>
          <objective-refer ref="O.SYSTEM_MONITORING">
            <rationale>The TOE mitigates the threat of malformed traffic causing a system crash by ensuring that any such instances are logged so that their cause can be diagnosed and prevented in the future.</rationale>
          </objective-refer>
          <objective-refer ref="O.TRAFFIC_FILTERING">
            <rationale>The TOE mitigates the threat of malformed traffic causing a failure of the TOE by providing a mechanism to prevent the TSF from processing it.</rationale>
          </objective-refer>
        </threat>
        
        <threat name="T.NETWORK_ACCESS">
          <description>An attacker may send traffic through the TOE that enables them to access devices in the TOE’s OE without authorization.</description>
          <consistency-rationale>
            The Base-PP does not define a threat for access to network resources because all of its security-relevant external interfaces define the network device as the endpoint. 
            This PP-Module defines interfaces where the TOE is facilitating a connection between two external entities, 
            such that traffic between them will flow through the TOE as opposed to into/out of the TOE. 
            This threat is consistent with the Base-PP because it is only applied to the interfaces defined in this PP-Module where it is relevant; it does not apply to the interfaces defined in the Base-PP.
          </consistency-rationale>
          <objective-refer ref="O.AUTHORIZED_ADMINISTRATION">
            <rationale>The TOE mitigates the threat of unauthorized network access by giving the administrator the ability to configure traffic filtering rules to block unauthorized traffic.</rationale>
          </objective-refer>
          <objective-refer ref="O.PROTECTED_COMMUNICATIONS">
            <rationale>The TOE mitigates the threat of unauthorized network access by enforcing the use of protected communications channels that prevent impersonation of legitimate subjects.</rationale>
          </objective-refer>
          <objective-refer ref="O.SYSTEM_MONITORING">
            <rationale>The TOE mitigates the threat of unauthorized network access by ensuring that any such instances are logged so that their cause can be diagnosed and prevented in the future.</rationale>
          </objective-refer>
          <objective-refer ref="O.TOPOLOGY_HIDING">
            <rationale>The TOE mitigates the threat of unauthorized network access by hiding its topology so that an attacker on an external network cannot discover or enumerate devices on the TOE’s internal network.</rationale>
          </objective-refer>
          <objective-refer ref="O.TRAFFIC_FILTERING">
            <rationale>The TOE mitigates the threat of unauthorized network access by enforcing traffic filtering rules that prevent devices on the internal network from being accessed.</rationale>
          </objective-refer>
        </threat>
        
        
        <threat name="T.RESOURCE_EXHAUSTION">
          <description>An attacker may transmit network traffic to the TOE that causes it to be unable to perform its functions on legitimate network traffic.</description>
          <consistency-rationale>
            The threat of network traffic causing the TOE to be unable to perform its functions is similar to T.SECURITY_FUNCTIONALITY_FAILURE in the Base-PP 
            because the intent of the threat is to cause the TSF to fail. 
            The Base-PP does not define denial of service protections because it does not define logical interfaces that are intended to process large volumes of network traffic. 
            This PP-Module extends the threat by defining a specific example of it that applies to an SBC device that has this functionality.
          </consistency-rationale>
          <objective-refer ref="O.AUTHORIZED_ADMINISTRATION">
            <rationale>The TOE mitigates the threat of resource exhaustion by giving administrators the ability to configure traffic rules so that traffic flooding attempts can be discarded.</rationale>
          </objective-refer>
          <objective-refer ref="O.RESOURCE_AVAILABILITY">
            <rationale>The TOE mitigates the threat of the transmission of network traffic that causes the inability of the TOE to perform its functions, by protecting against disruptive traffic.</rationale>
          </objective-refer>
          <objective-refer ref="O.SYSTEM_MONITORING">
            <rationale>The TOE mitigates the threat of unauthorized network access by ensuring that any such instances are logged so that their cause can be diagnosed and prevented in the future.</rationale>
          </objective-refer>
          <objective-refer ref="O.TRAFFIC_FILTERING">
            <rationale>The TOE mitigates the threat of resource exhaustion by providing the ability to filter network traffic that could cause a denial of service.</rationale>
          </objective-refer>
        </threat>
        
        
        <threat name="T.UNTRUSTED_COMMUNICATION_CHANNELS">
          <description>An attacker may acquire sensitive TOE or user data that is transmitted to or from the TOE because an untrusted communication channel causes a disclosure of data in transit.</description>
          <consistency-rationale>
            The threat of disclosure of data in transit is fundamentally the same as the NDcPP threat with the same name. This PP-Module extends the threat to apply to the external interfaces that are defined specifically in support of SBC functions.
          </consistency-rationale>
          <objective-refer ref="O.PROTECTED_COMMUNICATIONS">
            <rationale>The TOE mitigates the threat of disclosure of data in transit by enforcing the use of protected communications channels that prevent transmitted data from unauthorized disclosure.</rationale>
          </objective-refer>
        </threat>
        
        
        <threat name="T.USER_DATA_REUSE">
          <description>User data may be inadvertently sent to a destination not intended by the original sender, causing an unauthorized disclosure of the data.</description>
          <consistency-rationale>
            The Base-PP does not define a threat of user data transmitted to the wrong destination because all of its security-relevant external interfaces define the network device as the endpoint. 
            This PP-Module defines interfaces where the TOE is facilitating a connection between two external entities, 
            such that traffic between them will flow through the TOE as opposed to to/from the TOE. 
            This threat is consistent with the Base-PP because it is only applied to the interfaces defined in this PP-Module where it is relevant; it does not apply to the interfaces defined in the Base-PP.
          </consistency-rationale>
          <objective-refer ref="O.USER_DATA_DELIVERY">
            <rationale>The TOE mitigates the threat of inadvertently sending user data to an unintended destination by implementing measures that ensure that data is only sent to the intended recipient.</rationale>
          </objective-refer>
        </threat>
        
      </threats>
    </sec:Threats>
    <sec:Assumptions>
      All assumptions for the OE of the Base-PP also apply to this PP-Module. A.NO_THRU_TRAFFIC_PROTECTION is still operative, but only for the interfaces in the TOE that are defined by the Base-PP and not the PP-Module.
      <assumptions/>
    </sec:Assumptions>
    
    <sec:Organizational_Security_Policies>
      <!-- This PP-Module defines no additional organizational security policies beyond those specified in the NDcPP. -->
      <OSPs/>
    </sec:Organizational_Security_Policies>
  </sec:Security_Problem_Description>
  <sec:Security_Objectives>
    <sec:Security_Objectives_for_the_TOE>

      <SOs>
        
        <SO name="O.AUTHORIZED_ADMINISTRATION">
          <description>All network devices are expected to provide services that allow the security functionality of the device to be managed. 
            The SBC, as a specific type of network device, has a refined set of management functions to address its specialized behavior.
            <h:p/>
            <h:b>Addressed by:</h:b> FMT_SMF.1/SBC
          </description>
          <consistency-rationale>
            The NDcPP does not define any TOE objectives; instead, it maps SFRs directly to threats. 
            This TOE objective is consistent with the NDcPP because the individual security functions needed to satisfy the objective do not contradict with the security functions required by the NDcPP.
          </consistency-rationale>
          <addressed-by>FMT_SMF.1/SBC</addressed-by>
          <rationale>
            This SFR supports the objective by defining TSF management functions that require authorizations to use.
          </rationale>
        </SO>
        
        
        <SO name="O.PROTECTED_COMMUNICATIONS">
          <description>To mitigate the threat of data-in-transit disclosure, the SBC must ensure that remote communications are secured using appropriate means. 
            This includes the security of VVoIP signaling and media channels and Session Initiation Protocol (SIP) trunking, 
            in addition to any secure communications channels that are prescribed by the Base-PP such as communication with audit or authentication servers.
            <h:p/>
            <h:b>Addressed by:</h:b> FCS_TLSC_EXT.1 (refined from Base-PP), FCS_TLSC_EXT.2 (refined from Base-PP), FCS_TLSS_EXT.1 (refined from Base-PP), 
            FCS_TLSS_EXT.2 (refined from Base-PP), FIA_X509_EXT.1/Rev (refined from Base-PP), FIA_X509_EXT.2 (refined from Base-PP), 
            FIA_X509_EXT.3 (refined from Base-PP), FTP_ITC.1 (refined from Base-PP), FCS_SRTP_EXT.1, FIA_SIPT_EXT.1, FTP_ITC.1/ESC, FTP_ITC.1/VVoIP, FTP_ITC.1/H323 (selection-based)
          </description>
          <consistency-rationale>
            The NDcPP does not define any TOE objectives; instead, it maps SFRs directly to threats. 
            This TOE objective is consistent with the NDcPP because the individual security functions needed to satisfy the objective do not contradict with the security functions required by the NDcPP.
          </consistency-rationale>
          <addressed-by>FCS_TLSC_EXT.1 (refined from Base-PP)</addressed-by>
          <rationale>
            This SFR supports the objective by requiring TLS for SIP trunking and ESC signaling channel communications.
          </rationale>
          <addressed-by>FCS_TLSC_EXT.2 (refined from Base-PP)</addressed-by>
          <rationale>
            This SFR supports the objective by requiring mutually-authenticated TLS for SIP trunking.
          </rationale>
          <addressed-by>FCS_TLSS_EXT.1 (refined from Base-PP)</addressed-by>
          <rationale>
            This SFR supports the objective by requiring TLS for SIP trunking and ESC signaling channel communications.
          </rationale>
          <addressed-by>FCS_TLSS_EXT.2 (refined from Base-PP)</addressed-by>
          <rationale>
            This SFR supports the objective by requiring mutually-authenticated TLS for SIP trunking.
          </rationale>
          <addressed-by>FIA_X509_EXT.1/Rev (refined from Base-PP)</addressed-by>
          <rationale>
            This SFR supports the objective by defining requirements for the X.509 validation algorithm used by the TOE’s TLS implementation.
          </rationale>
          <addressed-by>FIA_X509_EXT.2 (refined from Base-PP)</addressed-by>
          <rationale>
            This SFR supports the objective by defining requirements for the X.509 validation algorithm used by the TOE’s TLS implementation.
          </rationale>
          <addressed-by>FIA_X509_EXT.3 (refined from Base-PP)</addressed-by>
          <rationale>
            This SFR supports the objective by defining a mechanism by which the TOE obtains the certificates it uses for TLS client and server connections.
          </rationale>
          <addressed-by>FTP_ITC.1 (refined from Base-PP)</addressed-by>
          <rationale>
            This SFR supports the objective by defining external interfaces that require protected communications as well as the trusted protocols used to protect those communications.
          </rationale>
          <addressed-by>FCS_SRTP_EXT.1</addressed-by>
          <rationale>
            This SFR supports the objective by defining the TOE’s implementation of the SRTP protocol that is used to protect VVoIP endpoint communications.
          </rationale>
          <addressed-by>FIA_SIPT_EXT.1</addressed-by>
          <rationale>
            This SFR supports the objective by defining secure behavior for SIP trunking.
          </rationale>
          <addressed-by>FTP_ITC.1/ESC</addressed-by>
          <rationale>
            This SFR supports the objective by defining how communications with an external ESC are protected.
          </rationale>
          <addressed-by>FTP_ITC.1/VVoIP</addressed-by>
          <rationale>
            This SFR supports the objective by defining how communications with an external VVoIP endpoint are protected.
          </rationale>
          <addressed-by>FTP_ITC.1/H323 (selection-based)</addressed-by>
          <rationale>
            This SFR supports the objective by defining H.323 as a permitted method of protected communications for when a conformant TOE implements this logical interface.
          </rationale>
        </SO>
        
      
        <SO name="O.RESOURCE_AVAILABILITY">
          <description>The SBC is not capable of performing its primary functionality if an attacker is able to prevent it from handling user data through a denial-of-service attack. 
            Therefore, the SBC is expected to provide security functions that allow it to prioritize its resources and protect against traffic that is designed only to disrupt availability of the device.
            <h:p/>
            <h:b>Addressed by:</h:b> FRU_PRS_EXT.1, FRU_RSA.1
          </description>
          <consistency-rationale>
            The NDcPP does not define any TOE objectives; instead, it maps SFRs directly to threats. 
            This TOE objective is consistent with the NDcPP because the individual security functions needed to satisfy the objective do not contradict with the security functions required by the NDcPP.
          </consistency-rationale>
          <addressed-by>FRU_PRS_EXT.1</addressed-by>
          <rationale>
            This SFR supports the objective by requiring the TSF to implement priority of service to ensure that low-priority traffic cannot cause a denial of service.
          </rationale>
          <addressed-by>FRU_RSA.1</addressed-by>
          <rationale>
            This SFR supports the objective by enforcing quotas for TSF resources to prevent denial of service.
          </rationale>
        </SO>
        
        
        <SO name="O.SYSTEM_MONITORING">
          <description>In order to ensure that potentially malicious activity is detected, the NDcPP requires security-relevant events to be audited. 
            The SBC also provides security functions to support system monitoring, defines additional security-relevant events for specific SBC functions, 
            and requires the use of a Network Time Protocol (NTP) server to provide accurate system time. 
            The SBC is also expected to support real-time system monitoring by providing the ability to automatically generate alerts when certain types of events occur.
            <h:p/>
            <h:b>Addressed by:</h:b> FAU_ARP_EXT.1, FAU_GEN.1/SBC, FAU_SAA.1, FAU_SEL.1
            <h:p/> <comment>[JF] This is saying that NTP is required but that's not currently backed up by SFRs. Should it be? e.g. mandate the NTP selection in Base-PP FPT_STM_EXT.1 and mandate FCS_NTP_EXT.1</comment>
          </description>
          <consistency-rationale>
            The NDcPP does not define any TOE objectives; instead, it maps SFRs directly to threats. 
            This TOE objective is consistent with the NDcPP because the individual security functions needed to satisfy the objective do not contradict with the security functions required by the NDcPP.
          </consistency-rationale>
          <addressed-by>FAU_ARP_EXT.1</addressed-by>
          <rationale>
            This SFR supports the objective by defining the ability to generate security violations that are transmitted to external entities.
          </rationale>
          <addressed-by>FAU_GEN.1/SBC</addressed-by>
          <rationale>
            This SFR supports the objective by iterating a Base-PP requirement to define additional auditable events that are specific to SBC functionality.
          </rationale>
          <addressed-by>FAU_SAA.1</addressed-by>
          <rationale>
            This SFR supports the objective by defining a set of rules to monitor auditable events for potential security violations. 
          </rationale>
          <addressed-by>FAU_SEL.1</addressed-by>
          <rationale>
            This SFR supports the objective by allowing for some monitoring functions to be selectively enabled and disabled as needed so that the generation of lower-priority 
            audit records can be suppressed when it is not practical to generate those records for performance reasons.
          </rationale>
        </SO>
        
        
        <SO name="O.TOPOLOGY_HIDING">
          <description>In order to ensure that there is no unauthorized disclosure of network information, 
            the SBC is expected to hide the topology of the protected network. 
            The SBC ensures no unauthorized disclosure by functioning as a B2BUA and by providing support for network address translation (NAT). 
            These mechanisms ensure that the intended recipient of data being transmitted through the TOE is not revealed and that devices inside the protected network are not directly accessible.
            <h:p/>
            <h:b>Addressed by:</h:b> FDP_IFC.1, FDP_IFF.1, FFW_NAT_EXT.1
          </description>
          <consistency-rationale>
            The NDcPP does not define any TOE objectives; instead, it maps SFRs directly to threats. 
            This TOE objective is consistent with the NDcPP because the individual security functions needed to satisfy the objective do not contradict with the security functions required by the NDcPP.
          </consistency-rationale>
          <addressed-by>FDP_IFC.1</addressed-by>
          <rationale>
            This SFR supports the objective by defining a B2BUA policy so that VVoIP endpoints are only connected to each other through the TOE as an intermediary.
          </rationale>
          <addressed-by>FDP_IFF.1</addressed-by>
          <rationale>
            This SFR supports the objective by defining the specific rules that the B2BUA policy enforces.
          </rationale>
          <addressed-by>FFW_NAT_EXT.1</addressed-by>
          <rationale>
            This SFR supports the objective by defining the use of NAT to obfuscate IP addresses of endpoint devices on the TOE’s internal network. 
          </rationale>
        </SO>
        
        
        <SO name="O.TRAFFIC_FILTERING">
          <description>In order to ensure that malicious traffic cannot compromise the SBC or devices on its protected network, 
            the SBC is expected to provide rudimentary traffic filtering capabilities. 
            This ensures that unauthorized TCP/UDP traffic is blocked and that all signaling and media traffic is first checked to be well-formed prior to performing any action on it.
            <h:p/>
            <h:b>Addressed by:</h:b> FFW_ACL_EXT.1, FFW_ACL_EXT.2, FFW_DPI_EXT.1
          </description>
          <consistency-rationale>
            The NDcPP does not define any TOE objectives; instead, it maps SFRs directly to threats. 
            This TOE objective is consistent with the NDcPP because the individual security functions needed to satisfy the objective do not contradict with the security functions required by the NDcPP.
          </consistency-rationale>
          <addressed-by>FFW_ACL_EXT.1</addressed-by>
          <rationale>
            This SFR supports the objective by defining capabilities for traffic filtering of network packets.
          </rationale>
          <addressed-by>FFW_ACL_EXT.2</addressed-by>
          <rationale>
            This SFR supports the objective by defining specific methods of stateful traffic inspection for specific protocols.
          </rationale>
          <addressed-by>FFW_DPI_EXT.1</addressed-by>
          <rationale>
            This SFR supports the objective by defining the capability to perform DPI for certain network traffic.
          </rationale>
        </SO>
        
        
        <SO name="O.USER_DATA_DELIVERY">
          <description>When user data is transmitted between calling parties, the calling parties expect that this data is only transmitted to the intended recipients. 
            The SBC is expected to provide this assurance through correctly functioning as a B2BUA and through correct implementation of SIP.
            <h:p/>
            <h:b>Addressed by:</h:b> FDP_IFC.1, FDP_IFF.1, FFW_NAT_EXT.1, FIA_SIPT_EXT.1, FIA_SIPS_EXT.1 (optional)
          </description>
          <consistency-rationale>
            The NDcPP does not define any TOE objectives; instead, it maps SFRs directly to threats. 
            This TOE objective is consistent with the NDcPP because the individual security functions needed to satisfy the objective do not contradict with the security functions required by the NDcPP.
          </consistency-rationale>
          <addressed-by>FDP_IFC.1</addressed-by>
          <rationale>
            This SFR supports the objective by defining a B2BUA policy that is used by the TOE to establish connections between VVoIP endpoints.
          </rationale>
          <addressed-by>FDP_IFF.1</addressed-by>
          <rationale>
            This SFR supports the objective by defining the rules that the B2BUA policy enforces.
          </rationale>
          <addressed-by>FFW_NAT_EXT.1</addressed-by>
          <rationale>
            This SFR supports the objective by requiring the use of NAT to maintain a unique relationship between how external entities identify entities on the TOE’s internal network and how they are actually addressed by that network.
          </rationale>
          <addressed-by>FIA_SIPT_EXT.1</addressed-by>
          <rationale>
            This SFR supports the objective by defining the use of SIP trunking, which requires authentication of endpoints to ensure data is only transmitted to the intended endpoint.
          </rationale>
          <addressed-by>FIA_SIPS_EXT.1 (optional)</addressed-by>
          <rationale>
            This SFR supports the objective by defining an optional capability to handle SIP registration in cases where the OE does not include an ESC that will provide that functionality.  
          </rationale>
        </SO>
        
        
      </SOs>
      </sec:Security_Objectives_for_the_TOE>
      
    <sec:Security_Objectives_for_the_Operational_Environment>
      All objectives for the OE of the Base-PP also apply to this PP-Module. OE.NO_THRU_TRAFFIC_PROTECTION is still operative, but only for the interfaces in the TOE that are defined by the Base-PP and not the PP-Module.
    </sec:Security_Objectives_for_the_Operational_Environment>
    <sec:Security_Objectives_Rationale>
      <!-- NOTE: This section should remain empty and is populated from the rationale tags in the previous sections.  -->
    </sec:Security_Objectives_Rationale>
  </sec:Security_Objectives>
  <sec:Security_Requirements>
    <base-pp id="ND" version="2.2e" name="Network Device" product="Network Device" short="ND" plural="Network Devices">
      <url><![CDATA[https://www.niap-ccevs.org/profile/Info.cfm?PPID=447&id=447]]></url>
  	  <cPP/>
      <modified-sfrs>
        <!-- per open comment, it's unclear whether we need to treat any other NDcPP SFRs as 'modified' (most notably FIA_X509_EXT.1/Rev and FTP_ITC.1, or are those completely separate from what is needed for auth server) -->

        <sec:from_nd_fia title="Cryptographic Support (FCS)">
          <f-component cc-id="fcs_tlsc_ext.1" name="TLS Client Protocol without Mutual Authentication"> 
            <consistency-rationale>
              This PP-Module mandates the inclusion of this selection-based SFR because it is required to implement the trusted communications required by the PP-Module.
            </consistency-rationale>
            <f-element>
              <title>
                This SFR is selection-based in the NDcPP but is mandated by this PP-Module because Transport Layer Security (TLS) is used for SIP trunking. An SBC implements TLS as both a client and a server.
              </title>
              <aactivity>
                <TSS>TBD
                <h:p/></TSS>
                <Guidance>TBD
                  <h:p/></Guidance>
                <Tests>
                  TBD
                </Tests>
              </aactivity>
            </f-element>
          </f-component>
      
            <f-component cc-id="fcs_tlsc_ext.2" name="TLS Client Support for Mutual Authentication"> 
              <consistency-rationale>
                This PP-Module mandates the inclusion of this optional SFR because it is required to implement the trusted communications required by the PP-Module.
              </consistency-rationale>
              <f-element>
                <title>
                  This SFR is optional in the NDcPP but is mandated by this PP-Module because SIP trunking requires mutually-authenticated TLS.
                </title>
                <aactivity>
                  <TSS>TBD
                    <h:p/></TSS>
                  <Guidance>TBD
                    <h:p/></Guidance>
                  <Tests>
                    TBD
                  </Tests>
                </aactivity>
              </f-element>
            </f-component>
      
          <f-component cc-id="fcs_tlss_ext.1" name="TLS Server Protocol without Mutual Authentication"> 
            <consistency-rationale>
              This PP-Module mandates the inclusion of this selection-based SFR because it is required to implement the trusted communications required by the PP-Module.
            </consistency-rationale>
            <f-element>
              <title>
                This SFR is selection-based in the NDcPP but is mandated by this PP-Module because TLS is used for SIP trunking. An SBC implements TLS as both a client and a server.
              </title>
              <aactivity>
                <TSS>TBD
                  <h:p/></TSS>
                <Guidance>TBD
                  <h:p/></Guidance>
                <Tests>
                  TBD
                </Tests>
              </aactivity>
            </f-element>
          </f-component>
          
          <f-component cc-id="fcs_tlss_ext.2" name="TLS Server Support for Mutual Authentication"> 
            <consistency-rationale>
              This PP-Module mandates the inclusion of this optional SFR because it is required to implement the trusted communications required by the PP-Module.
            </consistency-rationale>
            <f-element>
              <title>
                This SFR is optional in the NDcPP but is mandated by this PP-Module because SIP trunking requires mutually-authenticated TLS.
              </title>
              <aactivity>
                <TSS>TBD
                  <h:p/></TSS>
                <Guidance>TBD
                  <h:p/></Guidance>
                <Tests>
                  TBD
                </Tests>
              </aactivity>
            </f-element>
          </f-component>
      
        </sec:from_nd_fia>

        <sec:from_nd_fia title="Identification and Authentication (FIA)">
          <f-component cc-id="fia_x509_ext.1" iteration="Rev" name="X.509 Certificate Validation"> 
            <consistency-rationale>
              This PP-Module mandates the inclusion of this selection-based SFR because it is a dependency of the TLS requirements that it also mandates.
            </consistency-rationale>
            <f-element>
              <title>
                This SFR is selection-based in the Base-PP but mandatory in this PP-Module because the TOE’s TLS implementation requires appropriate X.509 functionality.
              </title>
              <aactivity>
                <TSS>TBD
                  <h:p/></TSS>
                <Guidance>TBD
                  <h:p/></Guidance>
                <Tests>
                  TBD
                </Tests>
              </aactivity>
            </f-element>
          </f-component>
          
          <f-component cc-id="fia_x509_ext.2" name="X.509 Certificate Authentication"> 
            <consistency-rationale>
              This PP-Module mandates the inclusion of this selection-based SFR because it is a dependency of the TLS requirements that it also mandates.
            </consistency-rationale>
            <f-element>
              <title>
                This SFR is selection-based in the Base-PP but mandatory in this PP-Module because the TOE’s TLS implementation requires appropriate X.509 functionality.
              </title>
              <aactivity>
                <TSS>TBD
                  <h:p/></TSS>
                <Guidance>TBD
                  <h:p/></Guidance>
                <Tests>
                  TBD
                </Tests>
              </aactivity>
            </f-element>
          </f-component>
          
          
          <f-component cc-id="fia_x509_ext.3" name="X.509 Certificate Requests"> 
            <consistency-rationale>
              This PP-Module mandates the inclusion of this selection-based SFR because it is a dependency of the TLS requirements that it also mandates.
            </consistency-rationale>
            <f-element>
              <title>
                This SFR is selection-based in the Base-PP but mandatory in this PP-Module because the TOE’s TLS implementation requires appropriate X.509 functionality.
              </title>
              <aactivity>
                <TSS>TBD
                  <h:p/></TSS>
                <Guidance>TBD
                  <h:p/></Guidance>
                <Tests>
                  TBD
                </Tests>
              </aactivity>
            </f-element>
          </f-component>
          
        </sec:from_nd_fia>
        <sec:from_nd_ftp>
          <f-component cc-id="ftp_itc.1" name="Inter-TSF Trusted Channel"> 
            <consistency-rationale>
              This PP-Module refines the Base-PP SFR to mandate the use of one of the trusted protocols defined by the Base-PP and 
              to optionally allow the use of a new protocol (SNMPv3) specifically for the use of the alert channel that is defined in the PP-Module.
            </consistency-rationale>
            <f-element>
              <title>
                The TSF shall be capable of using <h:b>TLS and</h:b> 
                <selectables>
                  <selectable>IPsec</selectable>
                  <selectable>SSH</selectable>
                  <selectable>DTLS</selectable>
                  <selectable>HTTPS</selectable>
                  <selectable><h:b>SNMPv3</h:b></selectable>
                  <selectable><h:b>no other protocol</h:b></selectable></selectables>
                to provide a trusted communication channel between itself and authorized IT entities supporting the following capabilities: audit server, 
                <selectables>
                  <selectable>authentication server</selectable>
                  <selectable><assignable>other capabilities</assignable></selectable>
                </selectables> that is logically distinct from other communication channels and provides assured identification of its end points and protection of the channel data from disclosure and detection of modification of the channel data.
              </title>
            </f-element>
            <f-element>
              <title>
                The TSF shall permit the TSF or the authorized IT entities to initiate communication via the trusted channel.
              </title>
            </f-element>
            <f-element>
              <title>
                The TSF shall initiate communication via the trusted channel for <assignable>list of services for which the TSF is able to initiate communications</assignable>.
              </title>
            <note role="application">
              TLS is mandated for SIP trunking as required by FIA_SIPT_EXT.1. SNMPv3 added as a selection to support FAU_ARP_EXT.1.
            </note>
              <aactivity>
                <TSS>TBD
                  <h:p/></TSS>
                <Guidance>TBD
                  <h:p/></Guidance>
                <Tests>
                  TBD
                </Tests>
              </aactivity>
            </f-element>
          </f-component>
        </sec:from_nd_ftp>
        

      </modified-sfrs>
      <additional-sfrs/>
      <con-toe> 
        When this PP-Module is used to extend the NDcPP, the TOE type for the overall TOE is still a network device. The TOE boundary is simply extended to include SBC functionality that is provided by the network device.
      </con-toe>
      <con-sec-prob/>
      <con-obj/>
      <con-op-en/>

      

    </base-pp>
    <man-sfrs>
      
      <sec:man_fau title="Security Audit (FAU)">
        <ext-comp-def title="Security Audit Automatic Response" fam-id="FAU_ARP_EXT">
          <fam-behavior>This family defines requirements for secure external transmission of detected security violations to the OE.  </fam-behavior> 
        </ext-comp-def>
        <f-component cc-id="fau_arp_ext.1" name="Security Audit Automatic Response"> 
          <consistency-rationale>
            This SFR applies to the generation of alerts when a given auditable event is detected, which is beyond the original scope of the Base-PP.
          </consistency-rationale>
          
          <comp-lev> defines the mechanism used by the TOE to securely transmit security alerts to the OE.  
          </comp-lev>
          <management>No specific management functions are identified.
          </management>
          <audit>There are no auditable events foreseen.
          </audit>
          <dependencies>FAU_SAA.1 Potential Violation Analysis<h:p/>
            FTP_ITC.1 Inter-TSF Trusted Channel
          </dependencies>
          
          <f-element>
            <title>
              The TSF shall be capable of using 
              <selectables>
                <selectable>TLS</selectable>
                <selectable>IPsec</selectable>
                <selectable>SSH</selectable>
                <selectable>HTTPS</selectable>
                <selectable>SNMPv3</selectable>
              </selectables> to transmit potential security violations to an external IT entity in the OE upon detection.
            </title>
            <ext-comp-def-title>
              <title>
                The TSF shall be capable of using <assignable>trusted channel defined in FTP_ITC.1</assignable> to transmit potential security violations to an external IT entity in the OE upon detection.
              </title>
            </ext-comp-def-title>
            <note role="application">
              The selected protocols must be reflected in FTP_ITC.1.
            </note>
            <aactivity>
              <TSS>TBD
                <h:p/></TSS>
              <Guidance>TBD
                <h:p/></Guidance>
              <Tests>
                TBD
              </Tests>
            </aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
        
        
        <f-component cc-id="fau_gen.1" name="Audit Data Generation (Session Border Controller)" iteration="SBC">
          <consistency-rationale>
            This SFR iterates a Base-PP requirement to define additional auditable events for SBC functionality that the Base-PP could not be expected to cover.
          </consistency-rationale>
<f-element>
            <title> The TSF shall be able to generate an audit record of the following auditable
              events: <h:ol type="a">
                <h:li>Start-up and shutdown of the audit functions;</h:li>
                <h:li>All auditable events for the [<h:i>not specified</h:i>] level of audit;</h:li>
                <h:li><h:b>All adminsitrative actions;</h:b></h:li>
                <h:li><h:b>[<h:i>Specifically defined auditable events listed in the Auditable Events table (<xref to="auditSBC"/>)</h:i></h:b></h:li>
              </h:ol>
            <h:table>
              <h:tr>
                <h:th>Requirement</h:th>
                <h:th>Auditable Events</h:th>
                <h:th>Additional Audit Record Contents</h:th>
              </h:tr>
              <h:tr>
                <h:td>FAU_ARP_EXT.1</h:td>
                <h:td colspan="2">None</h:td>
              </h:tr>
              <h:tr>
                <h:td>FAU_SAA.1</h:td>
                <h:td colspan="2">None</h:td>
              </h:tr>
              <h:tr>
                <h:td>FAU_SEL.1</h:td>
                <h:td colspan="2">None</h:td>
              </h:tr>
              <h:tr>
                <h:td>FCS_SRTP_EXT.1</h:td>
                <h:td colspan="2">None</h:td>
              </h:tr>
              <h:tr>
                <h:td>FDP_IFC.1</h:td>
                <h:td colspan="2">None</h:td>
              </h:tr>
              <h:tr>
                <h:td>FDP_IFF.1</h:td>
                <h:td>Any modifications to the B2BUA policy</h:td>
                <h:td>None</h:td>
              </h:tr>
              <h:tr>
                <h:td rowspan="3">FFW_ACL_EXT.1</h:td>
                <h:td rowspan="3">Application of traffic filtering rules</h:td>
                <h:td>Source and destination of observed traffic</h:td>
              </h:tr>
              <h:tr>
                <h:td rowspan="3">FFW_ACL_EXT.2</h:td>
                <h:td rowspan="3">Application of traffic filtering rules</h:td>
                <h:td>Source and destination of observed traffic</h:td>
              </h:tr>
              <h:tr>
                <h:td>Rule relevant to observed traffic</h:td>
              </h:tr>
              <h:tr>
                <h:td>Result of rule evaluation</h:td>
              </h:tr>
              <h:tr>
                <h:td rowspan="3">FFW_DPI_EXT.1</h:td>
                <h:td rowspan="3">Application of deep packet inspection rules</h:td>
                <h:td>Source and destination of observed traffic</h:td>
              </h:tr>
              <h:tr>
                <h:td>Rule relevant to observed traffic</h:td>
              </h:tr>
              <h:tr>
                <h:td>Result of rule evaluation</h:td>
              </h:tr>
              <h:tr>
                <h:td>FFW_NAT_EXT.1</h:td>
                <h:td colspan="2">None</h:td>
              </h:tr>
              <h:tr>
                <h:td rowspan="5">FIA_SIPS_EXT.1</h:td>
                <h:td rowspan="5">Call Detail Record (CDR)</h:td>
                <h:td>Calling party</h:td>
              </h:tr>
              <h:tr>
                <h:td>Called party</h:td>
              </h:tr>
              <h:tr>
                <h:td>Start time of the call</h:td>
              </h:tr>
              <h:tr>
                <h:td>Call duration</h:td>
              </h:tr>
              <h:tr>
                <h:td>Call type</h:td>
              </h:tr>
              <h:tr>
                <h:td>FIA_SIPT_EXT.1</h:td>
                <h:td>All SIP trunk authentication attempts</h:td>
                <h:td>Username and IP address of the servie provider</h:td>
              </h:tr>
              <h:tr>
                <h:td>FMT_SMF.1/SBC</h:td>
                <h:td>All management actions</h:td>
                <h:td>Identifier of initiator</h:td>
              </h:tr>
              <h:tr>
                <h:td>FRU_PRS_EXT.1</h:td>
                <h:td colspan="2">None</h:td>
              </h:tr>
              <h:tr>
                <h:td>FRU_RSA.1</h:td>
                <h:td colspan="2">None</h:td>
              </h:tr>
              <h:tr>
                <h:td rowspan="3">FTP_ITC.1/ESC</h:td>
                <h:td>Initiation of the trusted channel</h:td>
                <h:td rowspan="3">Identification of the initiator and target of the trusted channel</h:td>
              </h:tr>
              <h:tr>
                <h:td>Termination of the trusted channel</h:td>
              </h:tr>
              <h:tr>
                <h:td>Failure of the trusted channel functions</h:td>
              </h:tr>
              <h:tr>
                <h:td rowspan="3">FTP_ITC.1/H323 (selection-based)</h:td>
                <h:td>Initiation of the trusted channel</h:td>
                <h:td rowspan="3">Identification of the initiator and target of the trusted channel</h:td>
              </h:tr>
              <h:tr>
                <h:td>Termination of the trusted channel</h:td>
              </h:tr>
              <h:tr>
                <h:td>Failure of the trusted channel functions</h:td>
              </h:tr>
              <h:tr>
                <h:td rowspan="3">FTP_ITC.1/VVoIP</h:td>
                <h:td>Initiation of the trusted channel</h:td>
                <h:td rowspan="3">Identification of the initiator and target of the trusted channel</h:td>
              </h:tr>
              <h:tr>
                <h:td>Termination of the trusted channel</h:td>
              </h:tr>
              <h:tr>
                <h:td>Failure of the trusted channel functions</h:td>
              </h:tr>
         
            </h:table>
              <ctr ctr-type="Table" id="SBC">: Auditable Events</ctr>
            </title>
	    <note role="application">
	        The auditable events defined in the Auditable Events table are for the SFRs that are explicitly defined in this PP-Module. 
	        For any SFRs that are included as part of the TOE based on the claimed Base-PP, it is expected that any applicable auditable events defined for those SFRs in the Base-PP are also claimed as part of the TSF.
	        <h:p/>
	        The Base-PP iteration of the SFR also requires “all administrative actions” to be audited. When the TOE includes this PP-Module, 
	        it is expected that this will also include the administrative actions that support the PP-Module defined in FMT_SMF.1/SBC.
	        <h:p/>
	        For SFRs labeled as optional or selection-based, the auditable event is required only if the corresponding SFR is claimed.
	        <h:p/>
	        A CDR is expected to be generated at the start of a session, at the end of a session, and during a session at an interval or time period specified by the ST author.
	    </note>
</f-element>
  <f-element>
    <title>
      The TSF shall record within each audit record at least the following information: <h:ol type="a">
        <h:li>Date and time of the event, type of event, subject identity, and the outcome (success or failure) of the event; and</h:li>
        <h:li>For each audit event type, based on the auditable event definitions of the functional components included in the 
          PP<h:b>-Module</h:b>/ST, [<h:i>information specified in column three of the Auditable Events table (<xref to="auditSBC"/>)</h:i>].</h:li>
      </h:ol>
    </title>
  <aactivity>
    <TSS>TBD
      <h:p/></TSS>
    <Guidance>TBD
      <h:p/></Guidance>
    <Tests>
      TBD
    </Tests>
  </aactivity>
</f-element> 
        </f-component>
        
        
        <f-component cc-id="fau_saa.1" name="Potential Violation Analysis"> 
          <consistency-rationale>
            This SFR applies to the detection of auditable events as potential security violations requiring the generation of alerts, which is beyond the original scope of the Base-PP.
          </consistency-rationale>
          
          <f-element>
            <title>
              The TSF shall be able to apply a set of rules in monitoring the audited events and based upon these rules indicate a potential violation of the enforcement of the SFRs.
            </title>
          </f-element>
          <f-element>
            <title>
              The TSF shall enforce the following rules for monitoring audited events: <h:ol type="a">
                <h:li>Accumulation or combination of <assignable>subset of defined auditable events</assignable> known to indicate a potential security violation; </h:li>
                <h:li><assignable>any other rules</assignable></h:li>
              </h:ol>
            </title>
          
          <note role="application">
            Examples of monitored audited events include authentication failures, self-test failures, or environmental failures (e.g. temperature violation).
            </note>
            <aactivity>
              <TSS>TBD
                <h:p/></TSS>
              <Guidance>TBD
                <h:p/></Guidance>
              <Tests>
                TBD
              </Tests>
            </aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
        
        
        <f-component cc-id="fau_sel.1" name="Selective Audit"> 
          <consistency-rationale>
            This SFR applies to the behavior of the audit function with respect to the auditable events defined in this PP-Module. It does not affect the audit functions that apply to the Base-PP.
          </consistency-rationale>
          
          <f-element>
            <title>
              The TSF shall be able to select the set of events to be audited from the set of all auditable events based on the following attributes: <h:ol type="a">
              <h:li>[<h:i>event type</h:i></h:li>
              <h:li><assignable>list of additional attributes that audit selectivity is based upon</assignable></h:li>
              </h:ol>
            </title>
         
            <note role="application">
              The auditable events associated with traffic filtering rules (see the FFW_ACL_EXT.2 and FFW_DPI_EXT.1 rows in the Auditable Events table above) 
              may generate a significant volume of traffic that make them impractical to generate on a persistent basis. 
              The TOE must have the ability to generate these records when necessary but this SFR exists to allow for the generation of those events to be suppressed when the TOE is in its evaluated configuration.
            </note>
            <aactivity>
              <TSS>TBD
                <h:p/></TSS>
              <Guidance>TBD
                <h:p/></Guidance>
              <Tests>
                TBD
              </Tests>
            </aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
        
      </sec:man_fau>
     
     
      <sec:man_fcs title="Cryptographic Support (FCS)">
        
        <ext-comp-def title="Secure Real-Time Transport Protocol" fam-id="FCS_SRTP_EXT">
          <fam-behavior>This family defines requirements for the implementation of SRTP.</fam-behavior> 
        </ext-comp-def>
        <f-component cc-id="fcs_srtp_ext.1" name="Secure Real-Time Transport Protocol"> 
          <consistency-rationale>
            This SFR applies to the implementation of SRTP, which is a protocol that is not used for any Base-PP functionality.
          </consistency-rationale>
          
          <comp-lev> requires the TSF to implement SRTP in accordance with specified standards, and for some of this functionality to be configurable.
          </comp-lev>
          <management>The following actions could be considered for the management functions in FMT: <h:ul>
            <h:li>Configuration of ports and cryptography for signaling communications.</h:li>
          </h:ul>
          </management>
          <audit>There are no auditable events foreseen.
          </audit>
          <dependencies>FMT_SMR.1 Security Roles<h:p/>
            FTP_ITC.1 Inter-TSF Trusted Channel
          </dependencies>
          
          <f-element>
            <title>
              The TSF shall implement the Secure Real-Time Transport Protocol (SRTP) that complies with RFC 3711, 
              and use Security Descriptions for Media Streams (SDES) in compliance with RFC 4568 to provide key information for the SRTP connection. 
            </title>
          </f-element>
          <f-element>
            <title>The TSF shall implement SDES-SRTP supporting the following cipher suites: <selectables linebreak="yes">
              <selectable>AES_CM_128_HMAC_SHA1_80, in accordance with RFC 4568</selectable>
              <selectable>AES_CM_128_HMAC_SHA1_32, in accordance with RFC 4568</selectable>
              <selectable>AES_256_CM_HMAC_SHA1_80, in accordance with RFC 6188</selectable>
              <selectable>AES_256_CM_HMAC_SHA1_32, in accordance with RFC 6188</selectable>
              <selectable>AEAD_AES_128_GCM, in accordance with RFC 7714</selectable>
              <selectable>AEAD_AES_256_GCM, in accordance with RFC 7714</selectable>
            </selectables>
            </title>
            <ext-comp-def-title>
              <title>
                The TSF shall implement SDES-SRTP supporting the following cipher suites <assignable>list of supported cipher suites and the standard in which they are defined</assignable>. 
              </title>
            </ext-comp-def-title>
          
          <note role="application">
            This requirement specifies that the SRTP session that will be used to carry the VoIP traffic will be keyed according to an SDES dialog using one of the identified cipher suites. 
            The ST author should select all cipher suites that are supported.
            </note>
          </f-element>
          <f-element>
            <title>
              The TSF shall ensure the SRTP NULL algorithm <selectables>
                <selectable>is disabled</selectable>
                <selectable>can be disabled by a [<h:i>Security Administrator</h:i>]</selectable></selectables>.
            </title>
            <ext-comp-def-title>
              <title>
                The TSF shall ensure the SRTP NULL algorithm <selectables>
                  <selectable>is disabled</selectable>
                  <selectable>can be disabled by a <assignable>administrator role</assignable></selectable></selectables>.
              </title>
            </ext-comp-def-title>
          </f-element>
          <f-element>
            <title>
              The TSF shall allow the SRTP ports to be used for SRTP communications to be specified by a [<h:i>Security Administrator</h:i>].
            </title>
            <ext-comp-def-title>
              <title>
                The TSF shall allow the SRTP ports to be used for SRTP communications to be specified by a <assignable>administrator role</assignable>.  
              </title>
            </ext-comp-def-title>
          <aactivity>
              <TSS>TBD
                <h:p/></TSS>
              <Guidance>TBD
                <h:p/></Guidance>
              <Tests>
                TBD
              </Tests>
            </aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
        
     
      </sec:man_fcs>
      <sec:man_fdp title="User Data Protection (FDP)">
        
        <f-component cc-id="fdp_ifc.1" name="Subset Information Flow Control"> 
          <consistency-rationale>
            This SFR applies to the TOE’s implementation of a B2BUA policy, which applies to the TOE’s through-traffic interfaces and is therefore beyond the original scope of the Base-PP.
          </consistency-rationale>
          
          <f-element>
            <title>
              The TSF shall enforce the [<h:i>B2BUA policy</h:i>] on [<h:i>caller-callee pairs attempting to communicate through the TOE</h:i>].
            </title>

            <aactivity>
              <TSS>TBD
                <h:p/></TSS>
              <Guidance>TBD
                <h:p/></Guidance>
              <Tests>
                TBD
              </Tests>
            </aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
        
        <f-component cc-id="fdp_iff.1" name="Simple Security Attributes"> 
          <consistency-rationale>
            This SFR applies to the TOE’s implementation of a B2BUA policy, which applies to the TOE’s through-traffic interfaces and is therefore beyond the original scope of the Base-PP.
          </consistency-rationale>
          
          <f-element>
            <title>
              The TSF shall enforce the [<h:i>B2BUA policy</h:i>] based on the following types of subject and information security attributes: 
              <assignable>method by which the TSF identifies each endpoint for a call</assignable>. 
            </title>
          </f-element>
          <f-element>
            <title>
              The TSF shall permit an information flow between a controlled subject and controlled information via a controlled operation if the following rules hold: 
              [<h:i>when valid communication through the TOE is attempted, the TSF will establish a connection between itself and the caller; 
               the TSF will establish a second connection between itself and the callee; and the TSF will redirect all communications that it receives between the two endpoints out through the proper connection</h:i>]. 
            </title>
          </f-element>
          <f-element>
            <title>
              The TSF shall enforce the [<h:i>following configurable behavioral rules: 
              <selectables linebreak="yes"> 
                <selectable>Default-deny (allowlist) posture: If configured, the TSF will implicitly deny all information flows except for those explicitly authorized by the TSF</selectable> 
                <selectable>Default-allow (denylist) posture: If configured, the TSF will implicitly allow all information flows except for those explicitly denied by the TSF</selectable></selectables></h:i>]. 
            </title>
          </f-element>
          <f-element>
            <title>
              The TSF shall explicitly authorize an information flow based on the following rules: 
              [<h:i>if the TSF is operating in an allowlist posture, any calling parties that are present on the allowlist 
              (identifiable by calling number, source IP address, or communications protocols) are explicitly authorized</h:i>]. 
            </title>
          </f-element>
          <f-element>
            <title>
              The TSF shall explicitly deny an information flow based on the following rules: 
              [<h:i>if the TSF is operating in a denylist posture, 
                any calling parties that are present on the denylist (identifiable by calling number or source IP address, or communications protocols) are explicitly denied</h:i>].
            </title>
            <aactivity>
              <TSS>TBD
                <h:p/></TSS>
              <Guidance>TBD
                <h:p/></Guidance>
              <Tests>
                TBD
              </Tests>
            </aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
      </sec:man_fdp>
      <sec:man_ffw title="Firewall">
        <ext-comp-class class="Firewall (FFW)">
          <description>Firewall functionality involves selective processing of network traffic such that the traffic is routed or discarded based on some notion of whether the traffic is valid. 
            Requirements in this class define capabilities for these processing functions.</description>
        </ext-comp-class>
        <ext-comp-def title="Traffic Filtering" fam-id="FFW_ACL_EXT">
          <fam-behavior>
            This family defines requirements for controlling traffic filtering, including the use of stateful traffic filtering on protocols and ports.</fam-behavior> 
        </ext-comp-def>
        <f-component cc-id="ffw_acl_ext.1" name="Real-Time Communications Traffic Filtering"> 
          <consistency-rationale>
            This SFR applies to traffic filtering, which applies to the TOE’s through-traffic interfaces and is therefore beyond the original scope of the Base-PP.
          </consistency-rationale>
          
          <comp-lev> requires the TSF to implement traffic filtering rules based on network protocol attributes.
          </comp-lev>
          <management>The following actions could be considered for the management functions in FMT: <h:ul>
            <h:li>Configuration of traffic filtering rules.</h:li>
          </h:ul>
          </management>
          <audit>The following actions should be auditable if FAU_GEN Security audit data generation is included in the PP/ST: <h:ul>
            <h:li>Application of traffic filtering rules.</h:li>
          </h:ul>
          </audit>
          <dependencies>None
          </dependencies>
          
          <f-element>
            <title>
              The TSF shall perform traffic filtering on network packets processed by the TOE. 
            </title>
          </f-element>
          <f-element>
            <title>
              The TSF shall allow the definition of traffic filtering for real-time communications traffic using the following network protocol fields: 
              <h:ul>
                <h:li>IPv4 <h:ul>
                  <h:li>source address</h:li>
                  <h:li>destination address</h:li>
                  <h:li>transport layer protocol</h:li>
                </h:ul></h:li>
                
                <h:li>IPv6<h:ul>
                  <h:li>source address</h:li>
                  <h:li>destination address</h:li>
                  <h:li>transport layer protocol</h:li>
                </h:ul></h:li>
                
                <h:li>TCP <h:b>(for signaling channel)</h:b><h:ul>
                  <h:li>source port</h:li>
                  <h:li>destination port</h:li>
                </h:ul>
                </h:li>
                
                <h:li>UDP <h:b>(for signaling channel)</h:b><h:ul>
                  <h:li>source port</h:li>
                  <h:li>destination port</h:li>
                </h:ul>
                </h:li>
                
                <h:li>Distinct Interface <h:b>(physical vs virtual or trust zone, e.g., trusted vs untrusted)</h:b></h:li>
                
                <h:li><h:i>Application (Real-Time Communications Protocol) <h:ul>
                  <h:li>signaling protocols: <selectables><selectable>SIP</selectable><selectable id="filters_H323">H.323</selectable></selectables></h:li>
                </h:ul></h:i></h:li>
              </h:ul>
            </title>
            <ext-comp-def-title>
              <title>
                The TSF shall allow the definition of traffic filtering for real-time communications traffic using the following network protocol fields: 
                <h:ul>
                  <h:li>IPv4 <h:ul>
                    <h:li>source address</h:li>
                    <h:li>destination address</h:li>
                    <h:li>transport layer protocol</h:li>
                  </h:ul></h:li>
                  
                  <h:li>IPv6<h:ul>
                    <h:li>source address</h:li>
                    <h:li>destination address</h:li>
                    <h:li>transport layer protocol</h:li>
                  </h:ul></h:li>
                  
                  <h:li>TCP<h:ul>
                    <h:li>source port</h:li>
                    <h:li>destination port</h:li>
                  </h:ul>
                  </h:li>
                  
                  <h:li>UDP<h:ul>
                    <h:li>source port</h:li>
                    <h:li>destination port</h:li>
                  </h:ul>
                  </h:li>
                  
                  <h:li>Distinct Interface</h:li>
                  
                  <h:li><assignable>other protocols or protocol types</assignable></h:li>
                </h:ul>
              </title>
            </ext-comp-def-title>
          
          
            <note role="application">
              Real-time communications traffic can use multiple transport protocols and ports. 
              Therefore, traffic filtering rules should be defined using the network protocol fields above, and one type of traffic may require multiple rules to be applied.
              <h:p/>
              If “H.323” is selected in this requirement, the ST must include the selection-based SFR FTP_ITC.1/H323.
            </note>
          </f-element>
          <f-element>
            <title>
              The TSF shall allow the following operations to be associated with traffic filtering rules: permit or drop with the capability to log the operation <h:b>for each specific rule defined</h:b>.
            </title>
            <note role="application">
              Whether or not logging is performed may be applied to individual rules or groups of rules on an independent basis. 
              For example, if there are six rules defined, the TOE should allow for any subset of these rules to be logged, independent of one another.  
            </note>
          </f-element>
          <f-element>
            <title>
              The TSF shall allow the traffic filtering rules to be assigned to each distinct network interface.
            </title>
          </f-element>
          <f-element>
            <title>
              The TSF shall: <h:ul>
              <h:li>Accept a network packet without further processing of traffic filtering rules if it matches an allowed established session for the following protocols: TCP, UDP, based on the following network packet attributes: <h:ul> 
                <h:li>TCP: source and destination addresses, source and destination ports, sequence number, flags</h:li> 
                <h:li>UDP: source and destination addresses, source and destination ports</h:li>
              </h:ul>
              </h:li>
              <h:li>Remove existing traffic flows from the set of established traffic flows based on the following: <selectables>
                <selectable>session inactivity timeout</selectable>
                <selectable>completion of the expected information flow</selectable></selectables>.</h:li>
              </h:ul>
            </title>
          </f-element>
          <f-element>
            <title>
              The TSF shall process the applicable traffic filtering rules in an administratively defined order.
            </title>
          </f-element>
          <f-element>
            <title>
              The TSF shall deny packet flow if a matching rule is not identified.
            </title>
          
            <aactivity>
              <TSS>TBD
                <h:p/></TSS>
              <Guidance>TBD
                <h:p/></Guidance>
              <Tests>
                TBD
              </Tests>
            </aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
        
        
        
        <f-component cc-id="ffw_acl_ext.2" name="Stateful VVoIP Traffic Filtering"> 
          <consistency-rationale>
            This SFR applies to traffic filtering, which applies to the TOE’s through-traffic interfaces and is therefore beyond the original scope of the Base-PP.
          </consistency-rationale>
          
          <comp-lev> requires the TSF to perform stateful traffic filtering on traffic that matches certain unauthorized state conditions.
          </comp-lev>
          <management>No specific management functions are identified.
          </management>
          <audit>The following actions should be auditable if FAU_GEN Security audit data generation is included in the PP/ST: <h:ul>
            <h:li>Application of traffic filtering rules.</h:li>
          </h:ul>
          </audit>
          <dependencies>None
          </dependencies>
          
          <f-element>
            <title>
              The TSF shall perform stateful traffic filtering on the following VVoIP protocols: <selectables>
                <selectable>SIP</selectable>
                <selectable id="stateful_H323">H.323 (H.225, H.245)</selectable>
                <selectable>MGCP</selectable></selectables>.
            </title>
            <ext-comp-def-title>
              <title>
                The TSF shall perform stateful traffic filtering on the following VVoIP protocols:  <assignable>VVoIP protocols</assignable>.
              </title>
            </ext-comp-def-title>
            <note role="application">
              If “H.323” is selected in this requirement, the ST must include the selection-based SFR FTP_ITC.1/H323.
            </note>
          </f-element>

          <f-element>
            <title>The TSF shall enforce the following default stateful traffic filtering rules on all network traffic matching protocol types identified in FFW_ACL_EXT.2.1:<selectables linebreak="yes">
              <selectable>SIP traffic where a BYE message precedes an INVITE message</selectable>
              <selectable>H.225 traffic where an RCF reply precedes any other traffic</selectable>
              <selectable>H.245 traffic where a ResponseMessage precedes a RequestMessage</selectable>
              <selectable>MGCP traffic where a DLCX message precedes a CRCX message</selectable></selectables>.
            </title>
            <ext-comp-def-title>
              <title>
                The TSF shall enforce the following default stateful traffic filtering rules on all network traffic matching protocol types identified in FFW_ACL_EXT.2.1: <h:ul>
                  <h:li><assignable>default stateful traffic filtering rules</assignable></h:li>
                </h:ul>
              </title>
            </ext-comp-def-title>
            <note role="application">
              The stateful traffic filtering rules selected in FFW_ACL_EXT.2.2 must match the selections made for VVoIP protocols in FFW_ACL_EXT.2.1.
            </note>
          </f-element>
          <f-element>
            <title>
              The TSF shall terminate any connection found to be in violation of the default stateful traffic filtering rules and provide the ability to generate an audit record of the event.
            </title>
            <note role="application">
              Due to the potential for an SBC to receive large amounts of traffic that gets filtered by the default stateful traffic filtering rules, 
              this PP-Module only requires that the TSF have the ability to generate audit records for all events. 
              “Configure traffic filtering rules” in FMT_SMF.1/SBC provides an expectation that the administrator can determine which rules cause 
              audit records to be generated so that the environment is not producing an excessively large volume of audit data.
            </note>
          </f-element>
          <f-element>
            <title>
              The TSF shall dynamically open media ports to VVoIP protocol traffic upon negotiation of a session and close these ports upon termination of a session.
            </title>
          </f-element>
          <f-element>
            <title>The TSF shall not define a static range of ports to remain open indefinitely for the purpose of allowing VVoIP protocol traffic.</title>
          <aactivity>
              <TSS>TBD
                <h:p/></TSS>
              <Guidance>TBD
                <h:p/></Guidance>
              <Tests>
                TBD
              </Tests>
            </aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
        
        
        
        <ext-comp-def title="Deep Packet Inspection" fam-id="FFW_DPI_EXT">
          <fam-behavior>This family defines requirements for implementation of DPI functionality.</fam-behavior> 
        </ext-comp-def>
        <f-component cc-id="ffw_dpi_ext.1" name="Deep Packet Inspection"> 
          <consistency-rationale>
            This SFR applies to DPI, which applies to the TOE’s through-traffic interfaces and is therefore beyond the original scope of the Base-PP.
          </consistency-rationale>
          
          <comp-lev> defines traffic that the TSF is expected to be able to perform DPI on, the specific elements of that traffic that is subject to DPI, and the action that is taken when invalid traffic is discovered by the DPI mechanism.
          </comp-lev>
          <management>No specific management functions are identified.
          </management>
          <audit>The following actions should be auditable if FAU_GEN Security audit data generation is included in the PP/ST: <h:ul>
            <h:li>Application of DPI rules.</h:li>
          </h:ul>
          </audit>
          <dependencies>None
          </dependencies>
          
          <f-element>
            <title>
              The TSF shall implement DPI for the following protocols: <selectables>
                <selectable>H.323 (H.225, H.245)</selectable>
                <selectable>SIP</selectable>
                <selectable>RTP</selectable>
                <selectable>RTCP</selectable></selectables>. 
            </title>
            <ext-comp-def-title>
              <title>
                The TSF shall implement DPI for the following protocols: <assignable>communications protocols</assignable>.
              </title>
            </ext-comp-def-title>
            <note role="application">If “H.323” is selected in this requirement, the ST must include the selection-based SFR FTP_ITC.1/H323.</note>
          </f-element>
          <f-element>
            <title>
              The TSF shall enforce the following rules for DPI: <assignable>for each protocol listed in FFW_DPI_EXT.1.1, 
              list elements of the packet data that are examined for potentially malicious content or compatibility with the protocol definition</assignable>. 
            </title>
          </f-element>
          <f-element>
            <title>
              When traffic is found to be in violation of a DPI rule, the TSF shall take the following action:
              <selectables>
                <selectable>drop the traffic</selectable>
                <selectable>generate an audit record</selectable>
                <selectable>generate an alarm</selectable></selectables>.
            </title>
            <ext-comp-def-title>
              <title>
                When traffic is found to be in violation of a DPI rule, the TSF shall take the following action:
                <assignable>action taken in response to rule violation</assignable>.
              </title>
            </ext-comp-def-title>
            <aactivity>
              <TSS>TBD
                <h:p/></TSS>
              <Guidance>TBD
                <h:p/></Guidance>
              <Tests>
                TBD
              </Tests>
            </aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
        
        
        <ext-comp-def title="Network Address Translation" fam-id="FFW_NAT_EXT">
          <fam-behavior>This family defines requirements for implementation of NAT.</fam-behavior> 
        </ext-comp-def>
        <f-component cc-id="ffw_nat_ext.1" name="Topology Hiding/NAT Traversal"> 
          <consistency-rationale>
            This SFR applies to NAT, which applies to the TOE’s through-traffic interfaces and is therefore beyond the original scope of the Base-PP.
          </consistency-rationale>
          
          <comp-lev> requires the TSF to implement NAT for defined network protocols.
          </comp-lev>
          <management>The following actions could be considered for the management functions in FMT: <h:ul>
            <h:li>Configuration of NAT.</h:li>
          </h:ul>
          </management>
          <audit>TBD
          </audit>
          <dependencies>FDP_IFC.1 Subset Information Flow Control<h:p/>
            FMT_SMR.1 Security Roles
          </dependencies>
          
          <f-element>
            <title>
              The TSF shall support NAT of signaling and media channel traffic through the TOE that is mediated by the [<h:i>B2BUA policy</h:i>] defined by FDP_IFC.1.
            </title>
            <ext-comp-def-title>
              <title>
                The TSF shall support NAT of signaling and media channel traffic through the TOE that is mediated by the <assignable>information flow control policy</assignable> defined by FDP_IFC.1.
              </title>
            </ext-comp-def-title>
          </f-element>
          <f-element>
            <title>
              The TSF shall support NAT for the following protocols: <selectables>
                <selectable>SIP</selectable>
                <selectable>SIP-TLS</selectable>
                <selectable>H.225</selectable>
                <selectable>H.245</selectable></selectables>. 
            </title>
            <ext-comp-def-title>
              <title>
                The TSF shall support NAT for the following protocols: <assignable>list of protocols</assignable>.
              </title>
            </ext-comp-def-title>
          </f-element>
          <f-element>
            <title>
              The TSF shall use NAT to replace the IP address header value of traffic originating from the internal network with 
              <selectables>
                <selectable>the IP address of the TOE</selectable>
                <selectable>a [<h:i>Security Administrator</h:i>]-defined value</selectable></selectables>.
            </title>
            <ext-comp-def-title>
              <title>
                The TSF shall use NAT to replace the IP address header value of traffic originating from the internal network with 
                <selectables>
                  <selectable>the IP address of the TOE</selectable>
                  <selectable>a <assignable>administrator role</assignable>-defined value</selectable></selectables>.  
              </title>
            </ext-comp-def-title>
          </f-element>
          <f-element>
            <title>
              The TSF shall maintain a NAT table to ensure that traffic bound for the internal network is directed to only the intended recipient.
            </title>
            <aactivity>
              <TSS>TBD
                <h:p/></TSS>
              <Guidance>TBD
                <h:p/></Guidance>
              <Tests>
                TBD
              </Tests>
            </aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
        
        
        
      </sec:man_ffw>
      
      <sec:man_fia title="Identification and Authentication (FIA)">
        
        <ext-comp-def title="Session Initiation Protocol Trunking" fam-id="FAU_SIPT_EXT">
          <fam-behavior>This family defines requirements for SIP validation, authentication, and traffic encryption. </fam-behavior> 
        </ext-comp-def>
        <f-component cc-id="fia_sipt_ext.1" name="Session Initiation Protocol Trunking"> 
          <consistency-rationale>
            This SFR applies to SIP trunking, which is a logical interface that is beyond the original scope of the Base-PP.
          </consistency-rationale>
          
          <comp-lev> requires the TSF to implement SIP trunking using defined authentication and encryption methods.
          </comp-lev>
          <management>The following actions could be considered for the management functions in FMT: <h:ul>
            <h:li>Configuration of SIP communications.</h:li>
          </h:ul>
          </management>
          <audit>The following actions should be auditable if FAU_GEN Security audit data generation is included in the PP/ST: <h:ul>
            <h:li>All SIP trunk authentication attempts.</h:li>
          </h:ul>
          </audit>
          <dependencies>FCS_TLSC_EXT.1 TLS Client Protocol without Mutual Authentication<h:p/> 
            FCS_TLSC_EXT.2 TLS Client Support for Mutual Authentication<h:p/>
            FCS_TLSS_EXT.1 TLS Server Protocol without Mutual Authentication<h:p/>
            FCS_TLSC_EXT.2 TLS Server Support for Mutual Authentication<h:p/>
            FTP_ITC.1 Inter-TSF Trusted Channel 
          </dependencies>
          
          <f-element>
            <title>
          The TSF shall provide support for SIP trunking.
            </title>
          </f-element>
          <f-element>
            <title>
              The TSF shall require a service provider to provide valid identification in the form of a 
              <selectables>
                <selectable>username and password</selectable>
                <selectable>X.509 certificate</selectable></selectables> and IP address in order to establish a SIP trunk.
            </title>
          </f-element>
          <f-element>
            <title>The TSF shall require a service provider to provide a valid authentication credential in order to establish a SIP trunk.</title>
          </f-element>
          <f-element>
            <title>The TSF shall require a service provider to encrypt traffic using TLS in order to establish a SIP trunk.</title>
          <aactivity>
              <TSS>TBD
                <h:p/></TSS>
              <Guidance>TBD
                <h:p/></Guidance>
              <Tests>
                TBD
              </Tests>
            </aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
          
    
  
      </sec:man_fia>
      
      <sec:man_fmt title="Security Management (FMT)">
        <f-component name="Specification of Management Functions (SBC)" id="fel-managementfun-as" cc-id="fmt_smf.1" iteration="SBC">
			<consistency-rationale>
			  This SFR defines management functions for SBC that are not applicable to the Base-PP and therefore appropriately defined as a separate iteration of FMT_SMF.1.
			</consistency-rationale>
			<f-element>
			<title>The TSF shall be capable of performing the following management functions <h:b>related to SBC functionality</h:b>: [<h:i>Ability of a Security Administrator to:
			  <h:ul>
			    <h:li>Change a user's password</h:li>
			    <h:li>Require a user's password to be changed upon next login</h:li>
			    <h:li>Configure the auditable events that will result in the generation of an alarm</h:li>
			    <h:li>Configure the B2BUA policy</h:li>
			    <h:li>Configure traffic filtering rules</h:li>
			    <h:li>Configure auditable events</h:li>
			    <h:li>Configure NAT</h:li>
			    <h:li>Configure ports and cryptography for signaling and media communications</h:li>
			    <h:li>Configure SIP communications</h:li>
			  </h:ul></h:i>].
			</title>
			  <note role="Application">
			    This SFR defines additional management functions for the TOE beyond what is defined in the Base-PP as FMT_SMF.1. 
			    The TOE may have all management functionality implemented in the same logical interface; 
			    it is not necessary for “network device management” and “SBC management” to be implemented in separate interfaces.
			    <h:p/>
			    This PP-Module may rely on management functionality defined in the Base-PP to support the implementation of its functions. 
			    For example, the SBC portion of the TOE relies on the reliable time function that must be implemented by the Base-PP portion of the TOE. 
			    If the Base-PP implements this using NTP, the “Ability to set the time which is used for time-stamps” or “Ability to configure NTP” 
			    management function defined in FMT_SMF.1 in the Base-PP can be used to address this PP-Module’s dependency on reliable system time.
			    <h:p/>
			    The ’configurable auditable events’ function relates to FAU_SEL.1, specifically with respect to allowing a Security Administrator 
			    to determine whether a given event is auditable. As this refers to the events for the triggering of various filtering rules, 
			    it may be implicitly addressed through the ‘configure traffic filtering rules’ function, 
			    for example by explicitly defining a rule with a type that automatically requires it to be logged or a parameter that causes it to be logged if triggered.
			  </note>
			<aactivity>
			  <TSS>
			    TBD
			    <h:p/>
			  </TSS>
			  <Guidance> 
			    TBD
			    <h:p/>
			  </Guidance>
			  <Tests>
			  TBD 
			  </Tests>
			</aactivity>
		</f-element>
		</f-component>
        </sec:man_fmt>
      
      <sec:man_fru title="Resource Utilization (FRU)">
        
        <ext-comp-def title="Limited Priority of Service" fam-id="FRU_PRS_EXT">
          <fam-behavior>This family defines requirements for prioritizing communication packets and bandwidth.</fam-behavior> 
        </ext-comp-def>
        <f-component cc-id="fru_prs_ext.1" name="Limited Priority of Service"> 
          <consistency-rationale>
            This SFR applies to enforcement of bandwidth priority of service, which is a mechanism that is beyond the scope of the Base-PP and does not interfere with the ability of the Base-PP to process valid network traffic securely.
          </consistency-rationale>
          
          <comp-lev> requires the TSF to implement mechanisms to limit the amount of network bandwidth that is available to subjects based on certain attributes.
          </comp-lev>
          <management>No specific management functions are identified.
          </management>
          <audit>There are no auditable events foreseen.
          </audit>
          <dependencies>None
          </dependencies>
          
          <f-element>
            <title>
              The TSF shall assign a priority to each type of communications packet that traverses the TSF.
            </title>
          </f-element>
          <f-element>
            <title>
              The TSF shall ensure that each access to network bandwidth shall be mediated on the basis of the subject’s assigned priority and R-factor.
            </title>
            <aactivity>
              <TSS>TBD
                <h:p/></TSS>
              <Guidance>TBD
                <h:p/></Guidance>
              <Tests>
                TBD
              </Tests>
            </aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
        
        <f-component cc-id="fru_rsa.1" name="Maximum Quotas"> 
          <consistency-rationale>
            This SFR applies to enforcement of resource quotas, which is a mechanism that is beyond the scope of the Base-PP and does not interfere with the ability of the Base-PP to process valid network traffic securely.
          </consistency-rationale>

          <f-element>
            <title>
              The TSF shall enforce maximum quotas of the following resources: [<h:i>CPU, memory, <assignable>other resources</assignable></h:i>], 
              that [<h:i>subjects</h:i>] can use <selectables>
                <selectable>simultaneously</selectable>
                <selectable>over a specified period of time</selectable></selectables>. 
            </title>
            <note role="application">
              The intent of this SFR is for the TOE to be resistant to denial of service attacks.
            </note>
            <aactivity>
              <TSS>TBD
                <h:p/></TSS>
              <Guidance>TBD
                <h:p/></Guidance>
              <Tests>
                TBD
              </Tests>
            </aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
        
        
      </sec:man_fru>
 
      
	  <sec:man_ftp title="Trusted Path/Channels (FTP)">
		  <f-component cc-id="ftp_itc.1" name="Inter-TSF Trusted Channel (ESC Communications)" iteration="ESC">
		  <consistency-rationale>
		    The PP-Module iterates an SFR defined in the Base-PP to define a new external interface for communications with an ESC. 
		    This does not interfere with the ability of the Base-PP to enforce its security functionality on the existing logical interfaces.
			  </consistency-rationale>
			  <f-element>
			  <title>
			    The TSF shall provide a <h:b>signaling</h:b> channel between itself and <h:b>an ESC using TLS as specified in FCS_TLSC_EXT.1 and FCS_TLSC_EXT.2 and <selectables>
			      <selectable>DTLS as specified in FCS_DTLSC_EXT.1 and FCS_DTLSC_EXT.2</selectable>
			      <selectable>no other protocol</selectable></selectables></h:b> that is logically distinct from other communication channels 
			    and provides assured identification of its end points and protection of the channel data from modification or disclosure.
				  </title>
			    <note role="Application">
			      FCS_TLSC_EXT.1, FCS_TLSC_EXT.2, FCS_DTLSC_EXT.1, and FCS_DTLSC_EXT.2 are defined in the Base-PP.
			    </note>
				</f-element>
			    <f-element>
		<title>
		  The TSF shall permit [<h:i>the TSF</h:i>] to initiate communication via the trusted channel.
		</title>
	</f-element>
			  <f-element>
			    <title>The TSF shall initiate communication via the trusted channel for [<h:i>all communications with the ESC</h:i>]. 
			    </title>
			      
				  <aactivity>
				    <TSS>
				      TBD
				      <h:p/>
				    </TSS>
				    <Guidance>
				      TBD
				      <h:p/> 
				    </Guidance>
				    <Tests>
				      TBD
				    </Tests>
				  </aactivity>	  
			  </f-element>
		  </f-component>
	    
	    
	    <f-component cc-id="ftp_itc.1" name="Inter-TSF Trusted Channel (VVoIP Communications)" iteration="VVoIP">
	      <consistency-rationale>
	        The PP-Module iterates an SFR defined in the Base-PP to define a new external interface for communications with a VVoIP endpoint. 
	        This does not interfere with the ability of the Base-PP to enforce its security functionality on the existing logical interfaces.
	      </consistency-rationale>
	      <f-element>
	        <title>
	          The TSF shall <h:b>be capable of using SRTP, <selectables>
	            <selectable>SIP-TLS</selectable>
	            <selectable>IPsec</selectable>
	            <selectable>H.235</selectable>
	            <selectable><assignable>other protocols</assignable></selectable></selectables></h:b> 
	          to provide a <h:b>trusted</h:b> communication channel between itself and <h:b>authorized</h:b> IT 
	          <h:b>entities supporting the following capabilities: VVoIP signaling and media channels</h:b> that is
	          logically distinct from other communication channels and provides assured identification of its end points and protection of the channel data from modification or disclosure.
	        </title>
	        <note role="Application">
	          FCS_TLSC_EXT.1, FCS_TLSC_EXT.2, FCS_DTLSC_EXT.1, and FCS_DTLSC_EXT.2 are defined in the Base-PP.
	        </note>
	      </f-element>
	      <f-element>
	        <title>
	          The TSF shall permit [<h:i>the TSF, the authorized IT entities</h:i>] to initiate communication via the trusted channel.
	        </title>
	      </f-element>
	      <f-element>
	        <title>The TSF shall initiate communication via the trusted channel for <assignable>list of functions for which a trusted channel is required</assignable>. 
	        </title>
	        
	        <aactivity>
	          <TSS>
	            TBD
	            <h:p/>
	          </TSS>
	          <Guidance>
	            TBD
	            <h:p/> 
	          </Guidance>
	          <Tests>
	            TBD
	          </Tests>
	        </aactivity>	  
	      </f-element>
	    </f-component>
	    
      </sec:man_ftp>
        
    </man-sfrs>
   <opt-sfrs/>
    <sel-sfrs>
      
      <sec:sel_ftp title="Trusted Path/Channels (FTP)">
        
        <f-component cc-id="ftp_itc.1" name="Inter-TSF Trusted Channel (H.323 Communications)" iteration="H323">
          <depends on-sel="filters_H323" and="stateful_H323" also="H323_SDP"/>
          <consistency-rationale>
            The PP-Module iterates an SFR defined in the Base-PP to define a new external interface for communications using H.323. 
            This does not interfere with the ability of the Base-PP to enforce its security functionality on the existing logical interfaces.
          </consistency-rationale>
          <f-element>
            <title>
              <comment>[JF] need syntax for when there are >3 triggers for a sel-based SFR (FFW_ACL_EXT.1, FFW_ACL_EXT.2, FFW_DPI_EXT.1, FIA_SIPS_EXT.1)</comment>
              The TSF shall provide an <h:b>H.323</h:b> communication channel <h:b>in accordance with ITU-REC H.235.0</h:b> between itself and 
              <h:b>a gatekeeper using TLS as specified in FCS_TLSC_EXT.1 and FCS_TLSC_EXT.2 and <selectables>
                <selectable>IPsec as specified in FCS_IPSEC_EXT.1</selectable>
                <selectable>no other protocol</selectable>
              </selectables></h:b> that is logically distinct from other communication channels and provides assured identification of its end points and protection of the channel data from modification or disclosure.
            </title>
            <note role="Application">
              FCS_TLSC_EXT.1, FCS_TLSC_EXT.2, FCS_DTLSC_EXT.1, and FCS_DTLSC_EXT.2 are defined in the Base-PP.
            </note>
          </f-element>
          <f-element>
            <title>
              The TSF shall permit [<h:i>the TSF</h:i>] to initiate communication via the trusted channel.
            </title>
          </f-element>
          <f-element>
            <title>The TSF shall initiate communication via the trusted channel for [<h:i>all communications with the gatekeeper</h:i>]. 
            </title>
            <note role="application">
              This SFR is claimed if H.323 is specified as being supported by the TOE in FFW_ACL_EXT.1, FFW_ACL_EXT.2, FFW_DPI_EXT.1, or FIA_SIPS_EXT.1.
              <h:p/>
              FCS_TLSC_EXT.1, FCS_TLSC_EXT.2, and FCS_IPSEC_EXT.1 are defined in the Base-PP.
            </note>
            <aactivity>
              <TSS>
                TBD
                <h:p/>
              </TSS>
              <Guidance>
                TBD
                <h:p/> 
              </Guidance>
              <Tests>
                TBD
              </Tests>
            </aactivity>	  
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
        
      </sec:sel_ftp> 
      

    </sel-sfrs>
    <obj-sfrs>
    </obj-sfrs>
    <impl-dep-sfrs>
      
      <sec:impl_fia title="Identification and Authentication (FIA)">
        
        <ext-comp-def title="Session Initiation Protocol Registration" fam-id="FIA_SIPS_EXT">
          <fam-behavior>This family defines requirements for SIP registration.</fam-behavior> 
        </ext-comp-def>
        <f-component cc-id="fia_sips_ext.1" name="Session Initiation Protocol Registration"> 
          <consistency-rationale>
            This SFR applies to SIP registration, which is beyond the original scope of the Base-PP.
          </consistency-rationale>
          
          <comp-lev> defines requirements for how the TSF must implement SIP registration, including protocol implementations and constraints on authentication.
          </comp-lev>
          <management>The following actions could be considered for the management functions in FMT: <h:ul>
            <h:li>Configuration of SIP communications.</h:li>
          </h:ul>
          </management>
          <audit>The following actions should be auditable if FAU_GEN Security audit data generation is included in the PP/ST:<h:ul>
            <h:li>Call Detail Record (CDR)</h:li>
          </h:ul>
          </audit>
          <dependencies>None
          </dependencies>
          
          <f-element>
            <title>
              The TSF shall implement the <selectables>
                <selectable>SIP that complies with RFC 3261</selectable>
                <selectable id="H323_SDP">H.323 protocol that compiles with ITU-REC H.235.0</selectable></selectables> using the Session Description Protocol (SDP) complying with RFC 4566 to 
              describe the multimedia session that will be used to carry the VVoIP traffic.
            </title>
            <note role="application">
              If “H.323 protocol that complies with ITU-REC H.235.0” is selected in this requirement, the ST must include the selection-based SFR FTP_ITC.1/H323.
            </note>
          </f-element>
          <f-element>
            <title>
              The TSF shall require password authentication for SIP REGISTER function requests as specified in Section 22 of RFC 3261.
            </title>
          </f-element>
          <f-element>
            <title>
              The TSF shall support ESC authentication passwords that contain at least <assignable>positive integer of 8 or more</assignable> 
              characters in the set of [<h:i>upper case characters, lower case characters, numbers, and the following special characters: “!”, “@”, “#”, “$”, “%”, “^”, “&amp;”, “*”, “(“, and “)”, 
                and <assignable>other supported special characters</assignable></h:i>].
            </title>
            <ext-comp-def-title>
              <title>
                The TSF shall support ESC authentication passwords that contain at least <assignable>minimum numeric length</assignable> characters in the set of <assignable>supported character set</assignable>.
              </title>
            </ext-comp-def-title>
          </f-element>
          <f-element>
            <title>
              The TSF shall provide the ability to modify SIP header values for SIP traffic received by the TOE prior to retransmitting the traffic.
            </title>
          <note role="application">
            This SFR is optional because this functionality is not standard for SBCs because device registration can generally be handled by an ESC in the TOE’s OE. 
            However, in some cases, SIP registration directly to the SBC is required. 
            If an SBC advertises this service, it is expected that this functionality be included within the TOE boundary. 
            This SFR is therefore implementation-dependent based on whether the SBC has the capability to perform its own SIP registration of devices.
          </note>
            <aactivity>
              <TSS>TBD
                <h:p/></TSS>
              <Guidance>TBD
                <h:p/></Guidance>
              <Tests>
                TBD
              </Tests>
            </aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
      </sec:impl_fia>
      
    </impl-dep-sfrs>
  </sec:Security_Requirements>
  
  <appendix title="Implicitly Satisfied Requirements" id="satisfiedreqs">
    <h:b><ctr ctr-type="Table" pre="Table " id="imp-sat-reqs-table">: Implicitly Satisfied Requirements</ctr></h:b>
    <h:table>	
      <h:tr class="header"><h:td>Requirement</h:td><h:td>Rationale for Satisfaction</h:td></h:tr>
      <h:tr>
        <h:td><h:b>FMT_MSA.3 – Static Attribute Initialization</h:b></h:td>
        <h:td>
          FDP_IFF.1 has a dependency on FMT_MSA.3 to define the default security posture of security attributes for the purpose of information flow control enforcement. 
          This SFR has not been defined by this PP-Module because the enforcement of FDP_IFF.1 
          is not dependent on the initial state of security attributes. 
          For example, FDP_IFF.1.2 requires the TSF to determine if a communication attempt is valid before authorizing it. 
          This is true regardless of whether the default value of security attributes associated 
          with the connection attempt are permissive or restrictive; there is no difference in how the TSF determines “validity” in this case. 
          <h:p/>
          The default values of security attributes do not cause the information flow control policy to behave differently for those rules that must always be enforced by the TSF. 
          FDP_IFF.1.4 requires that all allowlisted calling parties be authorized while all denylisted calling parties be rejected. 
          It does not matter for the purpose of enforcing this SFR whether the absence of a calling party from both the allowlist and the denylist means they are authorized or rejected by default. 
        </h:td>
      </h:tr>
      <h:tr>
        <h:td><h:b>FMT_SMR.1 – Security Roles</h:b></h:td>
        <h:td>
          FCS_CKM.1 (which is defined in this PP-Module as
          FCS_CKM.1/VPN) requires FCS_CKM.4 to be claimed so that
          the generated keys are not disclosed through improper or
          nonexistent key destruction methods.<h:p/>
          Each of the supported Base-PPs except for the App PP define
          FCS_CKM_EXT.4 as an extended SFR, which defines key
          destruction functionality consistent with FCS_CKM.4, but with
          additional details that are specific to the respective
          technology types of the Base-PP. When the App PP is the
          Base-PP, this PP-Module defines its own instance of
          FCS_CKM_EXT.4 to achieve the same purpose. The
          dependency on FCS_CKM.4 is considered to be satisfied
          through the fact that a compliant TOE will always claim
          FCS_CKM_EXT.4, which is intended to satisfy the same
          purpose.
        </h:td>
      </h:tr>
    </h:table> 
  </appendix>
  
  <appendix title="Allocation of Requirements in Distributed TOEs" id="allocation">
    
    For a distributed TOE, the SFRs in this PP-Module need to be met by the
    TOE as a whole, but not all SFRs will necessarily be implemented by all components. The
    following categories are defined in order to specify when each SFR must be implemented by a
    component: <h:ul>
      <h:li><h:b>All Components ("All"):</h:b> All components that comprise the distributed TOE must
        independently satisfy the requirement.</h:li>
      <h:li><h:b>At least one Component ("One"):</h:b> This requirement must be fulfilled by at least one
        component within the distributed TOE.</h:li>
      <h:li><h:b>Feature Dependent ("Feature Dependent"):</h:b> These requirements will only be
        fulfilled where the feature is implemented by the distributed TOE component (note
        that the requirement to meet the PP-Module as a whole requires that at least one component
        implements these requirements if they are claimed by the TOE).</h:li></h:ul>
    The table below specifies how each of the SFRs in this PP-Module must be met, using the categories above.
    
    <h:table>
      <h:tr class="header">
        <h:td>Requirement</h:td>
        <h:td>Description</h:td>
        <h:td>Distributed TOE SFR Allocation</h:td>
      </h:tr>
      <h:tr>
        <h:td>FAU_ARP_EXT.1</h:td>
        <h:td>Security Audit Automatic Response</h:td>
        <h:td>Feature-dependent</h:td>
      </h:tr>
      <h:tr>
        <h:td>FAU_GEN.1/SBC</h:td>
        <h:td>Audit Data Generation (Session Border Controller)</h:td>
        <h:td>All</h:td>
      </h:tr>
      <h:tr>
        <h:td>FAU_SAA.1</h:td>
        <h:td>Potential Violation Analysis</h:td>
        <h:td>Feature-dependent</h:td>
      </h:tr>
      <h:tr>
        <h:td>FAU_SEL.1</h:td>
        <h:td>Selective Audit</h:td>
        <h:td>Feature-dependent</h:td>
      </h:tr>
      <h:tr>
        <h:td>FCS_SRTP_EXT.1</h:td>
        <h:td>Secure Real-Time Transport Protocol</h:td>
        <h:td>Feature-dependent</h:td>
      </h:tr>
      <h:tr>
        <h:td>FDP_IFC.1</h:td>
        <h:td>Subset Information Flow Control</h:td>
        <h:td>Feature-dependent</h:td>
      </h:tr>
      <h:tr>
        <h:td>FDP_IFF.1</h:td>
        <h:td>Simple Security Attributes</h:td>
        <h:td>Feature-dependent</h:td>
      </h:tr>
      <h:tr>
        <h:td>FFW_ACL_EXT.1</h:td>
        <h:td>Real-Time Communications Traffic Filtering</h:td>
        <h:td>Feature-dependent</h:td>
      </h:tr>
      <h:tr>
        <h:td>FFW_ACL_EXT.2</h:td>
        <h:td>Stateful VVoIP Traffic Filtering</h:td>
        <h:td>Feature-dependent</h:td>
      </h:tr>
      <h:tr>
        <h:td>FFW_DPI_EXT.1</h:td>
        <h:td>Deep Packet Inspection</h:td>
        <h:td>Feature-dependent</h:td>
      </h:tr>
      <h:tr>
        <h:td>FFW_NAT_EXT.1</h:td>
        <h:td>Topology Hiding/NAT Traversal</h:td>
        <h:td>Feature-dependent</h:td>
      </h:tr>
      <h:tr>
        <h:td>FIA_SIPS_EXT.1 (implementation-dependent)</h:td>
        <h:td>Session Initiation Protocol Registration</h:td>
        <h:td>Feature-dependent</h:td>
      </h:tr>
      <h:tr>
        <h:td>FIA_SIPT_EXT.1</h:td>
        <h:td>Session Initiation Protocol Trunking</h:td>
        <h:td>Feature-dependent</h:td>
      </h:tr>
      <h:tr>
        <h:td>FMT_SMF.1/SBC</h:td>
        <h:td>Specification of Management Functions (SBC)</h:td>
        <h:td>Feature-dependent</h:td>
      </h:tr>
      <h:tr>
        <h:td>FRU_PRS_EXT.1</h:td>
        <h:td>Limited Priority of Service</h:td>
        <h:td>Feature-dependent</h:td>
      </h:tr>
      <h:tr>
        <h:td>FRU_RSA.1</h:td>
        <h:td>Maximum Quotas</h:td>
        <h:td>Feature-dependent</h:td>
      </h:tr>
      <h:tr>
        <h:td>FTP_ITC.1/ESC</h:td>
        <h:td>Inter-TSF Trusted Channel (ESC Communications)</h:td>
        <h:td>Feature-dependent</h:td>
      </h:tr>
      <h:tr>
        <h:td>FTP_ITC.1/H323 (selection-based)</h:td>
        <h:td>Inter-TSF Trusted Channel (H.323 Communications)</h:td>
        <h:td>Feature-dependent</h:td>
      </h:tr>
      <h:tr>
        <h:td>FTP_ITC.1/VVoIP</h:td>
        <h:td>Inter-TSF Trusted Channel (VVoIP Communications)</h:td>
        <h:td>Feature-dependent</h:td>
      </h:tr>
      
      
    </h:table>
    
  </appendix>
  
  <appendix title="Entropy Documentation and Assessment" id="EAR">
    The TOE does not require any additional supplementary information to describe its entropy sources beyond the requirements outlined in the Base-PP.  
  </appendix>
  
  <bibliography>
    <cc-entry/>
    
    
    <entry id="bibNDcPP">
      <tag>NDcPP</tag>
      <description>
        <h:a href="https://www.niap-ccevs.org/MMO/PP/CPP_ND_V2.2E.pdf">collaborative Protection Profile for Network Devices</h:a>, Version 2.2e, March 23, 2020
      </description>
    </entry>
    
    <entry id="bibNDSD">
      <tag>NDcPP SD</tag>
      <description>
        <h:a href="https://www.niap-ccevs.org/MMO/PP/CPP_ND_V2.2-SD.pdf">Supporting Document - Evaluation Activities for Network Device cPP</h:a>, Version 2.2, December 2019
      </description>
    </entry>

  </bibliography>
</Module>
